AMELIA GIVENS

Experience Architecture student at Michigan State

Objective

I am a senior at Michigan State studying Experience Architecture (UX), graduating May 2024. I have an interest in UX research, along with creating solution-based digital designs for all.

I'm drawn to digital design due to its unique balance of creativity and analytical nature.

Skills

- Figma wireframing/prototyping
- UserZoom
- HTML and CSS
- · Microsoft SharePoint
- Data analytics
- Writing
- Problem solving

Contact

- East Lansing, MI
- 248-229-0137
- givensam@msu.edu
- www.linkedin.com/in/ameliagivens

Experience

DIGITAL WORKSPACE INTERN / CARHARTT

MAY 2023-DECEMBER 2023

- Conducted 10+ user tests through UserZoom ranging from click tests, card sorts, and basic usability for UX direct-to-consumer team.
- Redesigned internal IT SharePoint website, creating a more strategic navigation for associates to contact user support and submit tickets.
 Included the home page, IT help/training pages, navigation bar, and document libraries.
- Utilized Figma to create prototyped wireframes for testing purposes.

WEBSITE/UX ASSISTANT / MSU

OCTOBER 2022-PRESENT

ENVIROWEATHER

- Audit current site for accessibility issues and areas of improvement regarding usability and navigation patterns.
- Produce solution-based mockups in Figma with a focus on mobile-first design. These will then be used in a future website rewrite.
- Present mockups and prototypes to front and back-end developers and project manager once weekly. Feedback is then received and implemented.

GUEST ADVOCATE / TARGET

SEPTEMBER 2020-DECEMBER 2023

- Assisted guests with returns, purchases, order pickups, and drive-ups.
- Aided sales floor team with pushing extra stock within a time limit.
- Understood and followed retail and asset protection policies to ensure all guests had enjoyable experiences in-store.

Education

B.A. IN EXPERIENCE ARCHITECTURE /

2020-2024

MICHIGAN STATE UNIVERSITY

Coursework related to UX design, UX research, information architecture, graphic design, writing, digital rhetoric, and front-end web development.